Summer Lee (Nicklas Lee Woodman)

📍 Halifax, Nova Scotia | 📧 <u>hello@summerlee.design</u> | 🛕 <u>summerlee.design</u>



Product Designer

5 years of agency experience in a startup environment, communicating data informed design decisions cross-functionally with designers, developers, clients, and product managers. Specializing in: UX research, accessible UI design systems, information architecture, wireframing, prototyping, and visual design for mobile, desktop, and wearable tech.

Education

(2018-2021) NOVA SCOTIA COMMUNITY COLLEGE

Diploma - Business Administration

(2017-2018) SOBEY SCHOOL OF BUSINESS AT SMU

Foundation degree - Business/Commerce

(2012-2014) CENTRE FOR ARTS AND TECHNOLOGY

Advanced Diploma - Graphic Design & Web Development

Certificates

(2017) UNIVERSITY OF ALBERTA - REMOTE

Software Product Management

(2016) UNIVERSITY OF TORONTO - REMOTE

Building iOS Applications

(2015) UCI - REMOTE

Project Management Practices & Principles

Software Applications

FLUENT

- Figma, Sketch & InVision
- Adobe Illustrator & Photoshop
- Slack, Zoom, & Trello
- Microsoft 365 & Google Workplace
- Git, GitHub, & SourceTree

FAMILIAR

- Jira & Confluence
- Framer & WebFlow
- Google Analytics
- Amplitude & MixPanel
- Meta Business Suite
- HTML5, CSS3 & JavaScript
- React Native & Bootstrap
- Xcode & Android Studio

Professional Skills

FLUENT

- UX Research
- Wireframing
- Prototyping
- Visual Design
- Usability Testing
- Analytical Reporting
- iOS Human Interface Guidelines & Material Design

FAMILIAR

- UI Design Systems
- Lean Design & Agile Scrum
- Service Design
- WCAG Accessibility
- French (Canadian)

Experience

MOBILE UI/UX DESIGNER & SENIOR PRODUCT DESIGNER

MINDSEA, 2014-2016 & 2021-2023 (4 YEARS, 10 MONTHS)

A key member of the MindSea product design team, with a particular emphasis on human centred design, UI design systems, UX research, and product strategy for North American HealthTech startups and funded scale-ups.

- Collaborating closely across diverse teams including: management, software development, design, QA, sales and marketing to launch mobile iOS/Android apps.
- Leading client meetings, eliciting requirements and managing client relationships, effectively translating product strategy from stakeholders to development team.
- Consulting across management, development and design teams to coordinate accurate estimates/product requirements, while liaising daily with clients to update deliverables, budgets, schedules and manage expectations.
- Crafting communications to differentiate products from competitors, identifying MVP features and benefits for various user/customer segments within a market.
- Mocking up UI wireframes and technical UX documents to describe use cases and product requirements for marketing, development and internal departments.
- Testing usability of wireframes and rapid prototypes using Figma, Sketch, and inVision, while using GSuite tools such as Drive, Sheets, and Docs to report findings and data.
- Conducting data analysis of mobile app usage metrics, increasing engagement by interpreting user behaviour and designing functionality that promotes interaction.
- Researching using various UX methods including surveys, competitive analysis, and remote user interviews with software tools such as usertesting.com
- Design-reviewing front-end React Native UI components with developers to meet spec standards prior to submitting builds to Google Console & App Store Connect.
- Designing components to specification with development teams for use within internal design systems, ensuring they are scalable while meeting WCAG AA standards.
- Managing project deliverables using Scrum practices and lean design methodologies, while employing IDEO's design thinking principles/techniques to conduct user research.
- Facilitating technical CMS training sessions with clients for tools such as Firebase.
- Documenting and teaching internal design standards, guidelines, and processes.